Hayden McAlister

Email

haydenmcalister490 gmail.com

Phone 022 120 8324

Github

https://github.com/ hmcalister

Hayden McAlister

Software Engineer

About Me I am a Masters student of Computer Science at the University of Otago. My research has focused on artificial intelligence, neural networks, and high dimensional dynamic systems.

I enjoy investigating new ideas, trying new technologies, and solving problems both mathematical and engineering in nature. I have a strong background in computer science, as well as mathematics and physics, which has helped me develop problem solving skills.

Education

2023, University of Otago

MSc. Computer Science

2022, University of Otago

BSc(Hons), 1st Degree. Computer Science

2019 - 2021, University of Otago

BSc. Major in Computer Science, Minors in Physics, Mathematics

Research Projects

2022-2023, Interpretability of Neural Networks, University of Otago

Research project in interpretability of convolutional neural networks. Gained a lot of experience with very low level Tensorflow and other machine learning libraries. Worked independently to achieve project goals.

2023, Handwriting Analysis Project, University of Otago

Group research project in handwriting analysis. Attempted to classify handwriting quality using a variety of metrics.

Gained experience with data cleaning, signal processing, data visualization, and model comparisons.

2022, Natural Language Processing Project, University of Otago

Group research project in natural language processing. Goal was to create methods of measuring similarities between documents with respect to different metrics.

Gained experience with data cleaning, data processing, natural language processing, and natural language tools.

Hayden McAlister

Email

haydenmcalister490 gmail.com

Phone 022 120 8324

Github

https://github.com/ hmcalister

Experience

2021-2023, Lab Demonstrating (Various Papers), University of Otago

Involved presenting computer science topics to students. With more experience also involved creating and refining teaching resources for labs. Detailed achievements:

- Demonstrated for the papers:
 - COSC201: Algorithms and Data Structures
 - COSC202: Software Development
 - COSC203: Web, Databases, and Networks
 - COSC204: Computer Systems and Security
 - COSC301: Network Management and Security
 - COSC343: Artificial Intelligence
- Gained experience working with a team
- Gained experience explaining difficult concepts to the point of deep understanding

2020-2023, Tutoring, Freelance

Freelance tutoring for various subjects about the university. Specifically tutored in the fields of Computer Science, Mathematics, and Physics.

2020 - 2022, IT + Web Design, STMSNZ

Detailed achievements:

- Designed and created custom websites
- Aided with many mundane IT tasks, e.g.:
 - Email clients
 - Software bugs
 - Fixing user errors

Software Development Skills

Programming

- Python
 Go
 Rust
 Java
 C/C++
 Matlab
 Shell
 JS + Frameworks
- **Machine Learning + Data Science**
- Tensorflow
 Pytorch
 SpaCy
 Dash
 NumPy
 SciPy
 Pandas
 Polars
 SQL

Databases

MySQLSQLiteMongoDBCassandraMonarchGraphQL

Other Technologies

- Git/GitHub gRPC AWS/Cloud Bash/Shell Kubernetes
- Terraform

Hayden McAlister

Email

haydenmcalister490 gmail.com

Phone 022 120 8324

Github

https://github.com/ hmcalister

Awards

2023, Master's Research Scholarship, University of Otago

Awarded to students with high academic achievement moving into Masters research.

2021, *Sir George Grey Senior Scholarship*, University of Otago Awarded to the top Bachelors student in the Division of Science.

2021, **2022**, *Summer Research Scholarship*, University of Otago Awarded to students who undertake a research project over summer.

2020, *Robert Jack Physics Prize (200 Level)*, **University of Otago** Awarded to the top student in 200-level physics.

2019, *Academic Excellence Entrance Scholarship*, University of Otago Awarded to the students with high academic achievement entering the University of Otago.

2019, *Gordon Jupp Memorial Prize in Physics*, University of Otago Awarded to the top student in 100-level physics.

2019, *Dux Scholarship*, Otago Boys High School
Awarded to the Dux of Otago Boys High School to study at university.

Interests

Professional

Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Data Science, Data Visualization, Software Engineering, Software Development, Software Scalability

Personal

Mathematics, Physics, History, Guitar, Dungeons and Dragons, Magic: The Gathering